Hi, I'm Brunchandama. I'm a lead design engineer walking on Millicoat. So what is Millicoat?
It basically is a form of microarchitecture that runs on IBMC. And by microarchitecture, I mean, there's a
layer
invisible layer between what we publish in the principles of operations and
another layer which is a microarchitecture. And
And the reason why we have that is because every generation of z, the microarchitecture changes.
However, what we publish in the principles of operation, that does not change. We add stuff,
we don't remove stuff. We add new instructions, we don't remove instructions. So an instruction
that we introduced 10 years ago, functionally it does the same thing, but microarchitecture,
really how we get to that answer is very different. And in Millicoat, we make those changes so
that the operating system or the user of the program doesn't have to make those changes.
In addition to the instruction set, the implemented instruction set on the principle of operations,
Millicoat is also involved in a few other key aspects of IBMC. We do system initialization,
which basically means you pull an on the system, going to the IML steps, initial machine load,
that's IML. Millicoat is involved with virtualization. So you have a single resource, a system,
and you're going to divide it up into logical partitions and run different operating systems
in each partition. For that, to be possible, you need an instruction that's called
psi or start interpretive execution, and that instruction is implemented in Millicoat.
So that's Millicoat in a nutshell. As you can see, the things that we do on the system is
important, especially for recovery, for availability, and for serviceability. I've been enjoying
my work in Millicoat, and it's been fun joining so far. Thank you.